Chapter 1: Frontloading Mysteries

Welcome! It is highly recommended you check out the updated and properly-formatted version of this story (and some other goodies, like a glossary) at anarchyishyperbole dot com. I hope you enjoy it.

Ninety percent of everything was terrible. This was also true for people: ninety percent of them were dumb.

Reg Hig contemplated this unhappy fact as he stared at a copy of the Daily Prophet. The headline read, UNITY APPROACHES. Underneath, a smiling duo of clear importance were dipping their heads in identical bows before a dozen witches and wizards in trailing robes. The Tower and the Goddess, adding another country to their growing global hegemony.

It was tempting to crumple the paper in one angry fist, or perhaps to burn it into theatrical ashes. But he intended to scrutinize the lead story carefully, and he was certainly not going to buy a second copy of this propaganda sheet. The Daily Prophet had been a mouthpiece of the British ruling class since the time of his grandfather, and it was no different these days, now that a new Dark Lord and Lady had taken control.

It was almost comical the way each new Dark Lord followed the same playbook. The first step was to eliminate the main opposition, through assassination or spellcraft. The second step was to stack the local Thing (in Britain, it was the Wizengamot) with their followers. The third step was to take control of the leading newspaper. And last of all, almost as an afterthought, they would take over the local Ministry of Magic.

Still, Reg thought, it certainly made sense to use a tried-and-true method. History showed the wisdom. At the height of the Reign of the Eleusinian Mysteries, Sulla the Fortunate marched on Rome and took power by force, wresting it from the Optimates in the name of the Muggle masses. He ruled with absolute power. Forty years later, a successor did the same thing, championing the Muggle cause in the Senate and seizing power by force. Twenty years after that… well, you get the picture.

All else equal, a winning move would stay a winning move... until and unless you changed the rules. That's why the third successor of Sulla the Fortunate had quietly murdered all of his opposition, and had launched centuries of tyranny. Augustus Caesar had decided to change the rules, and he had done so with admirable effectiveness.

Reg stood from his desk chair, walking to the fireplace. He stamped his foot on a bright-green bellows at the fireplace entrance, barely breaking stride as he stepped into the flare of green flame and said, "Westphalian Council."

There was a brief moment as he walked from the travel room into the council chamber itself. For obvious reasons of security, the Floo network was not connected directly to a place of such power and discretion as the Westphalian Council's meeting chamber, or with the offices of any of the councilors.

Walking into the chamber, through a shower of Thieves' Downfall, Reg saw that there was only one other councilor present, sitting behind one of the tiny desks. Limpel Tineagar was a gangly woman, and she always looked a trifle silly folded up on the little chairs of the meeting chamber. As she leaned forward to peer at a parchment, her limbs seem to be too long and thin. Limpel resembled nothing so much as a robed spider.

"Reg," she said warmly, "how are you this morning?"

"Very well," he replied, walking down the tiers until he was on the level below her. He was almost a foot shorter than her, and if he had tried to take advantage of a rare opportunity to loom over someone by standing next to her, it would have seemed ridiculous to them both. Power should not be obvious.

"I assume you've heard of the French capitulation?" she asked, her tone less cheerful. "The cowards fall, one by one."

"That is why I am here," he said. "We must call a meeting, and we must discuss what the Americas will do. Inaction is no longer an option - not with Thing after Thing formally agreeing to the darkest of rituals! If we wait much longer, then it will be too late."

"A preview of your speech?" Limpel asked, her mouth twisting with amusement. She was a cynic, and had no native passion in her. "You rouse me with your stirring words."

Reg frowned slightly, and leaned forward, putting his hands on her desk and looking at her with frank directness. He was not an intimidating man, he knew. Short and ill-favored, he had a broad face with a plum nose and dark eyes. The dense black stubble around his mouth was irregular and resistant to every razor and charm. He was not charismatic and he was not scary.

But he was very persuasive.

"It's no joke, Limpel. Blocking the international statute only delayed Britain for a few years. Europe has now agreed to the Tower's demands almost as a whole, saving only the brave Cappadocians. France has already begun putting in place the necessary procedures to comply with the treaty. Thus far, it's only the harmless things - Healer's Kits and all that - but it won't be too much longer before Safety Poles are set up in Quiberon, Beauxbatons, Aix-en-Provence, and throughout Paris! Brainwashing available at the touch of a finger!"

Reg lifted a finger in the air.

"One Thing stands in the way: our council. We've been fighting this Atlantean nonsense for centuries, and we're about to lose for good. History will mark down this council as the one that failed… unless we take a stand.

"I don't know if you've ever noticed that, in an emergency, people in a crowd are slow to help. Someone gets hit by a Quaffle and falls into the stands, and everyone just stands back and looks shocked. No one in the crowd feels responsible - they're just watching. But when there's only one bystander, that person knows that it's on them. They have to intervene. And that's us, now. That's the Westphalian Council. We've spent years fighting for the rights of nonhumans and Muggles! We sent dozens to fight Grindelwald, and after Boston, we sent dozens to fight Voldemort. We're the only ally of the goblins that hasn't already sold their souls to this new Dark Lord.

"It's us. We're it. And if we fail, then that's the end of everything. Goblins in chains, Muggles start dying by the millions, and Westphalian Council becomes one more footnote at the bottom of the page, reading, 'Also destroyed in 1998 was the Westphalian Council, a once-important American wizarding union."

Limpel's smirk had left her face, and she was solemn. "You're right, of course. Sorry."

"No need for apologies, Limpel," Reg said, shaking his head and leaning back. "Just give me your word that you're with me. The next Dark Lord has risen, and we need to stop him. There is no one else… we are the battle line, here in this council."

She was nodding now, her mouth tight.

"So this isn't a speech, Limpel, but a request," he said, looking her in the eye and speaking with the earnestness of an honest man. "Will you help me stop Harry Potter-Evans-Verres, before he destroys the world as we know it?"

"You smile too much, 'Harry,' " Hermione Granger said to Nymphadora Tonks, lightly. "For anyone who knows the real fellow, it's a dead giveaway. You should spend more time looking serious or thoughtful. Alastor says that it's important to put yourself in the right mood, and so when he's being Harry he just pretends everyone else in the room is a child. He says Harry acts that way anyway, and it helps him be the right kind of condescending."

"Mad-Eye Moody says the meanest things I've ever heard anyone say about someone that they love like a son," Tonks said. She was running her finger up and down the lightning-bolt scar on her forehead. "It would be cute if it wasn't exactly as creepy as everything else Mad-Eye does."

Hermione shrugged. "I think it's sweet, really."

She pushed through the swinging wooden door as they exited Prestidigitation and Practicals. They were already being stared at, the moment they stepped out into Diagon Alley but that was okay. That was useful.

Hermione and Tonks-as-Harry made a beeline for the Safety Pole that had been fixed in Diagon Alley nearly two years ago. Their pace slowed as word spread. The Goddess was well-known and often out in public, but the Tower rarely ever left Hogwarts School for Witchcraft and Wizardry. To see him, you normally had to be either incredibly important or incredibly ill.

Harry was essentially in prison, Hermione reflected, as she gingerly moved through the crowd. He was trapped in his rooms at Hogwarts, forced to send magical doppelgangers to major events. If an official envoy insisted on meeting him in person, and that encounter seemed likely to require Harry's unique gifts, then that envoy simply had to come visit. As it turned out, this was better for everyone, on all counts. Harry was still not known for his social skills. There were other benefits, too. For example, the arrangement made it impossible for anyone to pressure a fake-Harry into an on-the-spot decision.

Ordinarily, Harry himself might have been the one to point out the advantages of being forced to confer and consider on any major decisions - of being pre-committed to that deliberation. It was right out of Schelling's The Strategy of Conflict, after all (page 30, her mind automatically supplied).

But Harry couldn't actually understand the whole concept, as she'd discovered when she'd tried to talk to him about it. Once he'd gotten important enough, he'd simply stopped wanting to leave the safety of Hogwart's. His Unbreakable Vow wouldn't permit him to "take any chances" with the destruction of the world, and at some point he had begun to consider that there was a small chance his presence might be necessary to save it. It was a very small chance, but it was a chance. He was too unique, perhaps - the single point of failure in too many possible systems. Hermione knew that this was why he did so much teaching. She had never felt the same constraint, though, despite her similar Vow. Was that humility on her part… or realism?

"Unbreakable Vows," Harry had said, when she had tried to encourage him to grapple with the situation, "are very effective. They don't work like genies in stories - I'm bound by the terms of the vow as it was meant, I think, in a way that makes me do my best with it. So while I understand what you're saying in the abstract, I don't want to want to leave Hogwart's or evade the Vow. Sorry."

It was sad. He was his own jailer.

Automatically, Hermione was smiling radiantly and giving small nods to people. At this point, basic public relations were on autopilot for her. It was easy. Her beauty helped. Maturity would probably have evened out her features anyway, but she also got a teensy-weensy bit of help from the dark ritual that had infused her with the unearthly magnificence of a unicorn. Plus, she'd been a world-renowned hero for several years now. As the old adage (and Sunshine Army slogan) had it, "Practice makes perfect."

"Thank heavens for you," a young woman said, reaching out to touch Hermione's arm. The woman looked to be something like thirty, but she stood with self-conscious straightness. She was probably one of the healed. Hermione nodded at her graciously, and eased by.

The prickling sensation in her arm began a moment later.

She glanced down, and saw a streak of something granular and colorless. Hermione's head whipped around, and she scanned for the young woman. Gone in the crowd. The prickling had already become a burning, and she even thought she could smell smoke. Some of the people nearby, already pressing close (which is how this happened, she thought) were backing away, their wands coming to hand and fear coming to their faces.

Hermione ripped the sleeve off of her robe, and scraped some of the substance off her skin. As she did so, she heard Tonks-as-Harry casting spells, waving her wand and calling, "Protego Totalum! Evanesco! Cave Inicum!" But there didn't seem to be any further immediate danger, and now the surface of Hermione's arm and robe were both burning with an oily black smoke. Even scarier: it didn't hurt that badly.

She plucked out her own wand, and spared a moment for the Fresh-Air Charm; a mint-scented breeze ruffled up around her and swept away the smoke. Keep the crowd safe. And she had to keep them safe from their own panic. She knew she was just being silly, and that she was buying into her own hype, and that wizards were essentially immune to crowd crushing (there weren't ever enough gathered in one place outside of a Quidditch arena, first of all, and wizards were naturally tough), but she couldn't help herself: she hunched over her arm and raised her wand to her throat. "Sonorus! Everyone, don't worry!" Her amplified voice was clear and strong, and accompanied by a reassuring smile. "Stay calm." Your arm is burning, and you can't really be seriously worried about them. On the other hand, they don't regenerate and we have an image to maintain. "Everything is all right." It's a powder, not acid, and it doesn't smell like Faux Floo. Is this a distraction? She glanced around. Tonks was next to her, wand raised, glancing back and forth from her to the crowd. The gathered wizards and witches were either frozen in place or backing away, with a few taking a cue from her freshening charm to put on Bubblehead Charms. No one was taking advantage of the disturbance to attack.

Almost too late, she saw the black knapsack lying on the ground at her feet.

"Waddiwassi!" The knapsack rocketed up into the air as Hermione cast the spell on it. It was an incredibly easy and quick spell to cast, a light tripping of syllables from the lips to the back of the mouth. Twice as fast as depulso and eight times as fast as wingardium leviosa - Hermione didn't know why anyone would use anything else.

With a cracking boom that sounded much like a thunderbolt, the backpack detonated.

Tonks-as-Harry turned to Hermione, even as the boom echoed around them and people were screaming, and hissed one angry word. "Malfoy."

Percy Weasley was maybe the best government employee imaginable, Harry Potter-Evans-Verres thought to himself. He watched the young man admiringly as Percy described the new accords reached within the International Magical Trading Standards Body. One could always find witches and wizards with the necessary competence and leadership, but it was so rare to find someone with actual perspective - someone who knew that unexciting things like standards for cauldron thickness really and truly mattered, and that a three percent increase in the cauldron failure rate meant thousands of Galleons in lost wealth (and perhaps even actual loss of life, if some poor potion brewer couldn't make it to a Safety Pole).

These attributes are why Percy was effectively in charge of the Ministry of Magic from his position as Senior Undersecretary to the Minister for Magic. He didn't think about outcomes in terms of narratives or story. He thought about them in more absolute terms: so many Galleons saved, people saved, options saved. Even better, Harry thought, Percy was absolutely loyal.

"...moved more quickly," the young man was saying, solemnly. "These larger Vanishing Cabinets - we're calling them Vanishing Rooms - do present a serious security risk, though. And there's a risk of splinching, with such a volume, if anyone is inside when the shipment goes through. You were absolutely right, though… we can move a thousand times as much now. It actually brings up an interesting problem. Apparently we're shipping out more than we're shipping in. It all comes down to…"

Reflexively, Harry considered if his appreciation of Percy's loyalty was a Voldemort thought, tuning Percy's report on trade deficits out of mind for a moment. Was it wrong to consider personal loyalty to himself as an inherently valuable trait in an ally? Perhaps it was, he thought. It was not consistent with how he valued his other lieutenants. Amelia or Mad-Eye would turn against him quickly if they thought he was corrupt or evil, and that was good. While obstacles in general wouldn't do him much good, experience had often shown that he tended to underestimate his own biases. Capable allies who could be relied upon to defy him, if needed, were invaluable.

Harry went to work, mentally, picking apart the thought and turning the instinct to his own use. In his youth, he had treated his mental simulation of Voldemort (his "dark side," he remembered with amusement) as a closed programming loop that would accept input ("This is my problem.") and output an answer ("Try killing everyone in your way, maybe?"). That answer would sometimes need to be rejected or modified in the fact of contrary ethical guidelines, of course, but at its core, he had treated the Voldemort thought-patterns as an opaque sort of special reasoning.

That had been silly, and the huge disadvantages had become obvious after a year spent clumsily clomping around the intricate plans of two geniuses. He had acted with the absolute self-assurance and total obliviousness of a first-year psychology student, and it was only thanks to the advantage of actually knowing the future that one of those geniuses had managed to succeed (almost despite Harry's best ignorant efforts).

So, he had spent some time integrating the Voldemort simulation into his own psyche, and now routinely examined his thinking to critically assess his success. Sunlight is the best disinfectant, after all, and he would have been a fool to ignore Amelia's concerns ("Young man, if there is a Voldemort in your head, then you can either crush it into submission or we can carve it out. The choice is yours.") Harry glanced down at the ring on his finger, an unadorned metal band.

Harry returned his full attention to Percy, hoping nothing important had been said in the meantime and feeling a little shabby about having let his thoughts wander. Fortunately, much of the report had been for the benefit of others. Harry had already studied sufficient economics, but much of his council was still learning the essentials. The education was necessary, since economics were a weapon and a tool of state.

"...so this is actually to our advantage, and we may be able to use it as leverage." Percy concluded. He glanced around the room for questions, then settled his rawboned frame back into his chair. He was a striking young man, tall and thin with the vivid red Weasley hair and freckles. He had once been balding and bespectacled, but Harry had taken care of that.

"Thank you," Harry said, smiling. "It's always good to have another tool to use, should we need it." Truth be told, it probably was never going to be useful. It was hard to even say that a trade deficit was a bad thing for anyone involved, and that was especially true with an economy nearly decoupled from labor. But it might be a propaganda point, to be brought up in a negotiation or something.

"Now let us turn to the next item on the agenda," he said, glancing down at the parchment. "Amelia, you had Ms. Bogdanov and Ms. Covenant meet with their respective Muggle equivalents in the Medicines and Health Products Regulatory Agency? How did that go?" Ilya Bogdanov and Tilly Covenant were in charge of the Office for the Detection and Confiscation of Counterfeit Defensive Spells and Protective Objects.

"Not very well, Harry," Amelia Bones said, rising from her seat in turn. She was a plain-looking young woman, with a square jaw and chestnut hair pulled back into a tight bun. She looked (unsurprisingly) much like Susan Bones, her niece. "Bogdanov didn't give it a chance, and came to me to tell me that it was, and I quote, 'a tragic mistake to think that Muggles should be in charge of any part of the Department of Magical Law Enforcement.' She specifically mentioned that the Muggles had proposed that anyone who tests magical devices should be blinded." Amelia leaned forward and glared at Harry. "I told you that this would happen, Harry."

Harry sighed. He'd thought they were further along than this. "The Muggles didn't mean that the testers should be literally blind. A blind study is ju-"

"A blind study is a study where the examiners keep themselves ignorant of the origin of what they're measuring, yes I know," Amelia interrupted, curtly. "You know that and I know that but these witches weren't looking for knowledge. They were just looking for an excuse not to change their minds."

"Yes… 'most people would rather die than think, and many do.'" Harry quoted. "But Amelia, we can't just fire the heads of every office, just because they're not working with us as smoothly as we'd like.". They'd had this argument before. Harry thought it was better to have the dozens of recalcitrant officials dragging their heels on the inside, rather than agitating on the outside. All the real troublemakers might have been decapitated in a single night, long ago, but that didn't mean it would be a good idea to give some of wizarding Britain's most prominent witches and wizards a direct reason to oppose the new regime. Amelia would have none of it, though.

"We don't have to fire them all. But we fired Shacklebolt, to make an example, and it wasn't enough. How about we just demote some of this dead weight, instead."

"And get around the Peter Principle? Hm." Harry paused for a moment. "You have a point there, actually. Table this now, maybe, and we'll work out the possibilities?"

Amelia nodded, just as the door burst open. Hermione and Tonks strode into the meeting room, clothes still damp from rapidly evaporating Thieves' Downfall. Tonks looked furious, and as her hair lengthened into her typical shoulder-length, multicolored long locks, it framed a iron scowl. Something had gone wrong, it would seem.

Like all rooms in the Tower, the meeting room was an odd quadrangle. It was an odd side-effect of the most important aspect of their security protocol, which required the entire Tower complex to be shaped as one giant triangle. It was odd, but it did mean that entrances could be particularly dramatic, which was useful for negotiations. The very shape of the room pointed everyone's attention at the narrow wall, where the open door framed an irritated Hermione Granger.

"Hello, everyone. Sorry for the rude entrance," she said. She glanced around at the group, which collectively represented most of the power of magical Britain, not to mention the greater part of Europe. Her eye paused for a second on Charlevoix, one of her Returned and a witch who had been instrumental in the recent French agreement. The excitable woman was almost out of her seat in alarm, scarred hands clenched on her chair. Hermione's glance communicated peace, and Charlevoix's face softened. Hermione turned to Harry, who had risen and was waiting patiently for her to speak.

"Harry," she said. "Malfoy just blew up a bomb in the middle of Diagon Alley. No one was hurt, but dozens could have been injured or killed. I know you have a plan, but that couldn't have been part of it. What is going on?"

She watched as he absorbed this information. Harry looked slightly surprised for a moment, and then his mouth pursed, and then his face relaxed.

"A Muggle device that casts deprimo," murmured Percy Weasley to the rest of the table. Amelia Bones already seemed to know, as did a few others (like the Muggle Liaison), but most had seemed uncomprehending. There was quiet murmuring in response.

"Was any property destroyed?" Harry asked, seriously.

"No," she said.

"Thanks to Hermione," Tonks said indignantly, from her spot behind the Goddess.

"No one was hurt and no property destroyed… was it a very small bomb? No, you took care of it. Did you put it into a pouch with an Undetectable Extension Charm, or something?" He looked thoughtful.

She shook her head. "No. Wait, would that even work?"

They both paused for a second to consider it, but he was the first to shake his head. "Not really, I don't think… although it might contain the blast and direct its force out of the opening of the pouch." He made a note on the margin of the parchment in front of him - an agenda to their meeting, she thought. "We should look into that."

"Especially now that Malfoy's started using bombs," Hermione said, archly. "Harry, you look like you understand what's going on, and that you're not worried. That makes me worried. This is a new level, and it could have killed a lot of people. But you don't seem to be taking it seriously. Just what is going on?"

Harry shook his head, reaching up to tuck a lock of his hair back behind his ear. She had noticed that he usually tied it back these days, but he'd left it loose this morning. Also, he was wearing Muggle clothes - a three-piece grey suit, with a blue silk tie. It looked rather well on his short and spare frame, but he tended to favor wizard's robes, these days. Were these subtle signs of distress at his imprisonment? Maybe he - or his subconscious - was feeling the effects of the long confinement. She set the thought aside for later consideration.

"We're at war, Hermione. You know that." At least Harry no longer looked so sure of himself, although it was probably only because he was worried about her. "They're going to keep ramping things up until they get a reaction, or until we capitulate on something."

Cedric Diggory spoke up from the end of the table, his voice kind but firm. "And that doesn't worry you, Harry?" The young auror looked skeptical.

"There's a plan. We're on track - two new Unspeakables arrived with reports just today, and there are new breakthroughs." Harry looked around the room. No one looked reassured. "I know I've been saying that for a long time-"

"For years," Tonks interrupted. She sounded frustrated.

"-I've been saying that for years, yes." Harry smoothly continued. "But you have to trust me on this. We can beat Malfoy and the whole faction… it will happen." His eyes moved from face to face, asking their trust. "There's a plan. It has been extremely complicated and unbelievably secret, but very soon now we will beat Narcissa, once and for all."

Sometime later, a young man with a lightning-bolt scar on his forehead sat down with a sigh on a small wooden stool. He was alone, and this room was private, admissible only to him. He could slump wearily without worrying about his posture. No one could see.

In front of him, on another wooden stool identical to his own, was a small black box. It was smooth and shiny, marred only by the pair of small hinges and the ornate lock that held its lid on. He stared at the box sightlessly for a while as he thought, letting his eyes glaze over and his mind wander.

Harry sat like that for a long time. Eventually, he blinked rapidly and returned to himself. He spoke to the box, quietly.

"I'd like to talk. But I won't let you out."

Chapter 18: Protagonists

Excerpt from a speech given on the floor of the Council of Westphalia by Reg Hig:

This is not the ideal world, witches and wizards of the Council. In the ideal world, we would not be concerned about getting the best deal… we would be the ones setting the terms. In the ideal world, Merlin would never have used force to master magic-kind in every state and nation, and placed us all under ten generations of British dominance. In the ideal world, this Council would not even be necessary, and our purpose - the protection of the rights of every people - every people, I say, Councilor Strongbound, goblins and centaurs included! - would be a fait accompli.

But we don't live in that ideal world. We live in this world, and if we wish to responsibly advise the leaders of the Americas, we must view the world with clear eyes. It's not enough to see the world as it should be… we must also see how it is. If your wand is broken, no amount of wishing and bloviating will make it work… you must fix it, and only then can you curse your enemies!

We have all seen terrible things, and fought terrible villains. I remember the fires of Grindelwald's scum, and the green light of Voldemort's death-dealing. This is a fight that is no less serious, and it needs serious people. It needs people who can act with a free hand.

I urge this Council to vote in favor of the proposal, and empower our negotiators… let them have the power to strike and relent as necessary, rather than hobbling them with intercontinental shackles. Let us take this moment and seize our opportunities! Let us arm our negotiators with a sword, so they may strike down our foes and cut through our shackles! I urge you all: vote in favor!

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Lawrence Ludwig Bradwian was special. He'd been special almost from the moment he was born. His great-aunt Corliss had been both a seer and a famous Keeper for the Wimbourne Wasps, and at the moment that Ludwig was born, she had fallen from her broom in a trance - letting the Quaffle through the goal - and had prophesied that a child of her family had been born who would " bring down a great house in a time of endless strife, when all the worlds narrow to two." The goal was more widely reported than the prophecy, since it was the Chudley Cannons' first goal of the season, but nonetheless everyone knew that Lawrence was a child of destiny.

Perhaps because of this special destiny, Lawrence grew up to be a confident boy. He had a poise about him that translated into natural leadership. Not many children had his sort of self-awareness, or his willingness to stand out from the crowd. It's often a sign of a difficult home life - even of abuse. Lawrence had a perfectly happy home life, on the other hand, except for the fact that he was continually made aware of the grand future that lay before him. The prophecy was vague, but phrased so powerfully that everyone knew Lawrence would leave his mark on the world.

In 1995, he was sorted into Slytherin, and embarked on quite a career of adventure as one of the first Silver Slytherins. They were a new breed, with new heroes: the few Slytherin aurors like Andromeda Tonks; Draco Malfoy and Narcissa Malfoy; Head of House Horace Slughorn; and businessmen like Perigold Pucey. They took their lead in school from upperclassman Blaise Zabini, who proudly said that they were the truly pure in ambition.

"Ambition believes in things that work, above everything else," Zabini said, standing dramatically in front of a window. "Blood purity, studying, science, or pickles… it doesn't matter. Ambition is about success."

Lawrence agreed.

In his first year, Lawrence single-handedly helped rescue a half-giant named Turm, who had taken refuge in the Forbidden Forest to escape his human relatives, the Meroveni-Bowles. Turm had thought he would be safe within the wards of the school, in the dangerous depths of the woods, but there had been six Meroveni-Bowles children at Hogwarts, and they had been planning to murder their half-brother. Lawrence had saved Turm from an elaborate series of traps constructed in the Forest, although he'd been unable to prove to the Headmistress that the Meroveni-Bowles - siblings from a respected and wealthy Hufflepuff/Ravenclaw family - were at fault.

In his second year, Lawrence and his friend Annabeth Dankgesang solved the mystery of the Shrieking Shack. They discovered a secret passageway under the Whomping Willow that led all the way from Hogwarts to Hogsmeade, and found out that the famously "haunted" house was inhabited only by Euphorics, who spread rumors about gruesome murders and vicious ghosts to discourage visitors from intruding on their operation. Minister for Magic Scrimgeour had personally congratulated Lawrence and Annabeth for helping break up the largest elixir distribution ring in the country. Unfortunately, Lawrence had also made an enemy of Sammy Meroveni-Bowles, a boy in their own year who Lawrence suspected might have been involved in smuggling supplies.

In his third year, Lawrence and Annabeth met and befriended Moaning Myrtle, one of the ghosts of Hogwarts, and she had told them of the Deluminator, an artifact created by Albus Dumbledore and stored in the Room of Requirement. Seeking out the Room of Requirement, they found the Deluminator - and a meeting of the Meroveni-Bowles, who were planning to steal Helga Hufflepuff's Cup from Smith Manor. Lawrence and Annabeth foiled the burglary and exposed the Meroveni-Bowles, leading to the two oldest children being expelled and the rest of them closely watched. The dramatic duel with Sammy Meroveni-Bowles had ended in a stalemate, that night, but at least he would be on a short leash from then on. Unfortunately, during the night of excitement and intrigue, the Cup was still stolen… and no one knew who did it!

Was it Lawrence's special destiny that led him to such adventures - was being a child of prophecy some sort of special invisible mark, that made trouble seek out the young do-gooder? Or had that fate just made into him the sort of person who wasn't afraid to investigate the ample mysteries and intricate plots of the world's foremost school of magic? It's hard to say. But it was Lawrence's fourth year, now, and everyone was holding their breath to see what was going to happen - and whether or not Lawrence and Annabeth's friendship would blossom into something more.

At the moment, the pair were in the Slytherin common room, and Annabeth was attempting to discern the secrets of their only clue to the Caper of the Cup: a small wooden abacus the size of her palm, dropped by a shadowy figure last year after an exciting chase and brief scuffle in Smith Manor.

"I think it's enchanted," Annabeth said, touching one of the wooden beads gently. She was a slight girl, her hair in neat dreadlocks, and her lips pursed in concentration. "I think it's the Protean Charm."

"Difficult magic. Hard to do, and bloody expensive to hire," Lawrence said. He eyed the abacus warily. "Any way to trace the other things linked to it?"

"No," said Annabeth. "Or, at least, I don't know how." She set the abacus down on the table in front of them, sighing.

"I'm sure I've seen one of these before…" said Lawrence. He closed his eyes, trying to let his mind free-associate and chase down the memory. Annabeth watched him thoughtfully, letting her eyes linger on his olive skin and the sharp planes of his face. She glanced away when he opened his eyes, grinning. "I've got it! Remember when Blaise brought that Silver who works in the Tower to speak to us? Auror Pirrip? And he came to talk to us about true ambition and all that… and his friend waited for him?"

Annabeth's eyes widened. "Yes… oh, Merlin, you're right! He bumped into the other auror with him, whatsherface, when they were leaving, and she dropped something! She got so angry at him and said all those words that we went to look up in the library, right after! I think it was one of these!"

"An auror device, then? Just for Tower aurors? Or something else entirely?" said Lawrence, narrowing his eyes and squinting at the small brown device. The little abacus had five rows of ten beads. They were stiff and not easy to move by mistake. The device looked unused, but enchanted objects often looked new even after a century of use.

"Easy enough to eliminate a few 'hypotheses,' " Annabeth said, smiling. Lawrence grinned. Neither of them had joined the Science Program - it limited your career options too much, since taking the extra, unorthodox classes made it harder to get your N.E.W.T.s in traditional subjects - but they'd both taken Muggle Studies and knew the basics. Annabeth would have been a natural at science.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

HYPOTHESIS 1: ALL AURORS

Annabeth got into position at the entrance to the History of Magic classroom. Professor Palma de Mallorca wasn't inside - they'd already checked - so she was able to stand just outside the door within the alcove, out of sight. She got the abacus out, holding it in her palm. Then she looked down the corridor. Lawrence was there, sitting on a windowsill, a book in his lap. He was watching a pair of aurors stationed at the end of the hall: one of the dozen that were situated in various places in Hogwarts. He looked at Annabeth, and she nodded. He fixed his eyes on the aurors, and then nodded in his own turn.

Annabeth flicked three of the beads in the top row to one side. Somewhere, all the abacuses linked by the Protean Charm to this one mimicked its movements. It was a way to signal, and even if they didn't know the appropriate messages or code, they did know that the recipients would need to look at their own copies. The little abacuses were too small and fiddly to interpret by feel.

Lawrence kept a careful watch on the aurors at the end of the hall, but they didn't change their behavior at all. They just kept quietly chatting, their hands folded casually into their sleeves. They weren't on very high alert - despite the supposed necessity of their presence, thanks to the existence of the Tower, they seldom had much to do. There were rumors that patients had escaped the Receiving Room and gone running around the school, but no one had ever actually seen such a thing first-hand, as far as Lawrence could discover. He wasn't sure he believed it. No one even really knew where the Receiving Room actually was in the school, for that matter (except the professors and aurors, he supposed). So far as he could actually verify, the only thing the aurors ever did was occasionally act to break up a fight or stop some bullying.

After as much as ten minutes had passed, Lawrence looked over at Annabeth and shook his head. No luck.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

HYPOTHESIS 2: TOWER AURORS

"What if they use Legilimency on me?" asked Lawrence, nervously. "They'll know I'm lying… they'll know everything." He glanced at his robes. "They might just guess from how much I'm sweating!"

"Just… try to be casual! They distribute Safety Sticks to like… a thousand countries these days! That Receiving Room must be busting, and no one's going to want to chat. Plus, Gregorius' cousin Lammie went on a lark, and he says that all that happened was that they owled Lammie's parents." Annabeth said, shrugging. "You'll be fine!"

"It knocks you out, you know… they might find the abacus while I'm unconscious," Lawrence said, shifting in his seat. "I wish we could figure out some way to do it with both of us, like last time. It'd be okay-" He cut himself off before he could finish the sentence with "if you were there." He blushed.

Annabeth was blushing now, too, although it wasn't as noticeable. She looked away and said hurriedly, with a smile, "Look just do it, you big kneazle!"

Lawrence stared at the Safety Stick in his hands and gulped… but anything was better than being right here, right now. It was too… too much. He snapped the Safety Stick with one strong thumb. There was a moment of wrenching force around his middle, and then darkness.

He awoke to a sudden unveiling of consciousness, as though a black curtain had been lifted from his awareness. There was no grogginess, and Lawrence was familiar enough with the process to expect the stunning (everyone knew the procedure to go to the Tower, since it was part of the first lectures on safety, and Lawrence's uncle had been rejuvenated), but it was still disorienting.

"Hello, son," said a young-looking witch, who was standing next to him. He was lying down on one of the cots. Lawrence became aware that she was holding his hand, and it twitched involuntarily. The witch just went on smiling pleasantly, and spoke again. "It's okay, you're in the Tower. We couldn't find anything wrong with your ABCs, and you don't seem to be hurt… can you tell me what's wrong?" She was extremely nice and extremely firm in a way that tolerated no dissembling. Her white robes were neat and trim, and her features were firm - snub nose, red hair, freckles, and sharp gaze.

"Oh Merlin… I'm in the Tower?!" Lawrence said. He was feeling a little panicky at the prospect of being caught, and so this performance didn't take much pretending. "But I didn't… oh, no! I'm so sorry… I had a Stick in my rear pocket! Annabeth shoved me... " He trailed off, letting the lie fade on his lips. He sat up and swiveled his legs off the cot, and buried his face in his hands, releasing the healer's hand. The contact was making him uncomfortable, as though she could tell his true thoughts by touch.

"I see... " said the healer. Her voice was neutral, in the way of someone reserving judgment without wishing to give offense. This must happen all of the time, and Lawrence was pretty young… she probably saw children doing this for fun, just for the experience of it, all the time. "Well, this is very serious, you know that, right? There are six people who spent quite a while scanning and working to help you, and they could have been helping people who really needed it. Sick people, injured people, or dying people. I see you're a Hogwarts student… what's your name?"

"Lawrence Bradwian," he replied, speaking as miserably as he felt.

"We keep track of everyone who 'accidentally' comes here. I'll let the arithmancer know… and he'll let the Headmistress know," the healer said. She stepped back from the screened-in little cubicle in which they were sitting. Lawrence glanced around. White tiled floors and ceiling, a plain little metal table, and a plain metal cot laid with white linen. Everything was as generic as something you might Transfigure, if you were hastily creating something new. He supposed they were in the main clinic ward, or something… details on the layout and details had been more scarce when he and Annabeth had asked around; everyone focused on the aurors and healing. Oh, Merlin… why did we ask around like that, how stupid… if anyone does doubt this 'accident,' it'll be easy to find out how curious we've been about the Tower! Lawrence tried to freeze his face in its current dismay, so that he didn't visibly dissolve into horror.

"I don't want you to think that you shouldn't get a new Stick, or let this stop you from visiting us in a real emergency, Lawrence," the healer said. She glanced away from him, and waved someone over. He took the opportunity to shove his hands in his pockets.

"Serge, would you help this young man, please? He needs to speak to Tommy or someone else, and then he needs to go back to… well, class, I suppose," the healer said to someone who had just walked up, past the edge of the white screen and out of sight.

"Certainly, Beneficent," said the unknown man. He stepped up to where Lawrence could see him… and it was an auror. A hulking man, six and a half feet if he was an inch, and twenty stone if he was a pound. Serge the Auror had a thick neck and a shaved head, and when he lifted a guiding hand to Lawrence, it looked more like architecture than anatomy, in terms of scale. The auror smiled kindly.

"Have a good afternoon, Lawrence," Beneficent said to him. She was smiling again… she'd apparently decided that she believed him. Or that she should be merciful. "Be more careful, okay?" Giving a half-wave, she was gone before he could answer.

Lawrence slid forward and stood up, stepping a little awkwardly to where Serge was standing, outside the cubicle. He glanced to the left and right. There looked to be at least a hundred similar cubicles stretching to either side, with an ample corridor down the middle. Lawrence could see two dozen people or more… healers, aurors, and people in random dress who must be patients. Several patients were unconscious and limp in the air, suspended by a spell as they were briskly taken down the corridor - entering or leaving, he supposed.

"Wow," he said.

"Not as fancy as you expected, I bet," said Serge with a smile.

No better time. Lawrence flicked four or five beads on the abacus in his pocket, and watched.

In the span of the next fifteen seconds, he counted two aurors and three healers who paused at the signal, and at least appeared to look at something from their pockets. Not every auror, and not every healer… only those five. What is worse, it looked to him like they were doing so furtively. They all looked with cupped hands, one of the healers ended a conversation and stepped away from the other person, and one of the aurors ducked almost out of sight into a cubicle.

"I'm not sure what I expected," said Lawrence. "But it wasn't this."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

HYPOTHESIS 3: OH MERLIN I DON'T EVEN WHAT

"So… it's not all aurors, or even all Tower aurors… it's just some of the healers and aurors in the Tower? That's good news!" said Annabeth. They were scrunched together on a bench in the Great Hall - luncheon was the only time Lawrence could find to meet, since he was serving detentions in the evening. It was Inigo Imago's birthday, and in honor of the legendary seer, the rolls and muffins were enchanted to hang suspended above the tables, spinning in tight orbits. It was said to resemble the movement of the heavenly spheres. The wide table in front of them was also filled with meats, cheeses, and platters of pickles. There was also some sort of curry, although neither Lawrence nor Annabeth was particularly interested in it.

"How can that possibly be good news?!" said Lawrence, wheeling around to face her. He held an uneaten but enormous sandwich in his hands. "It means… well, I'm not sure what it means, but it's something sinister! A secret cabal within the Tower! A cabal that stole the Cup!"

"Oh, just stop and think for a moment. There are all kinds of non-sinister possible explanations, right?" Annabeth said, picking a sesame roll out of the air. She tore it apart, absently, as she spoke. "Just because one of the people who stole the cup was a part of whatever group we're talking about, here, doesn't mean the group was involved. If we found a Gryffindor robe, it wouldn't mean there was a Gryffindor conspiracy to steal the Cup… just that one Gryffindor was involved. We have narrowed down the list of suspects, a lot. It's good news."

Lawrence sullenly took a bite out of his sandwich, declining to respond until a respectable amount of time had passed. After a while, though, he turned to Annabeth and said something witty and cutting, even though he said it around a mouthful of food that made it completely unintelligible.

"Gross," Annabeth said, making a face. "Slow down, or you'll choke."

Lawrence abandoned the effort, and concentrated on chewing. Annabeth went on, saying, "Okay, so we should probably go tell the Headmistress, immediately. There's no reason to wait. She and the Tower and all those important people can figure this out."

"No," said Lawrence, urgently. "That won't work. Listen, who was most likely to notice that Sammy and his siblings were up to no good? What sort of person?"

"A student, of course," said Annabeth. "Or a professor."

"And which students, specifically?" said Lawrence, raising his eyebrows.

"Us, I suppose. I mean, we've been tangling with them for years. There was Turm and the Shrieking Shack and Myrtle and… yes, if anyone was going to get suspicious, it was going to be us," Annabeth said, guardedly.

"And what would we be expected to do, if we found a clue?" said Lawrence.

"...report it to the Headmistress? But wait, you can't possibly think that this is a trap? If this conspiracy involves the Headmistress, then I think we've already lost. And anyway, how could you even think that!? You know what she's like! And how would that trap even work… you're saying that… I don't even know what you're saying!" Annabeth sounded scandalized and shocked and scornful, all in equal measure.

"Fair enough, okay," said Lawrence. He switched tactics. "But maybe she's just not powerful enough. We need to go right to the top. There's only one person who can sort this out… one person who can figure out the conspiracy and get back the Cup."

"First of all, you don't know that there's a conspiracy. The abacus might not be related. Second of all, there's no way we could get a private message to Minister N'Goma… there are probably eight people assigned just to read her owls. Third of all-"

"No, no," said Lawrence. "I mean the Tower. Let's go give the abacus to Dean Potter! He'll help us get back the Cup!"

Annabeth paused, then frowned, suspiciously. "You just want an excuse to talk to him and bring us to his attention." She thought for a moment, then brightened. "That's an excellent idea. He's almost as important as the Minister for Magic, anyway… and he's not accountable to anyone. A good person to know, and this is a good excuse to talk to him."

It was just like Professor Slughorn always said: the more people you know, the more people who can help you.

"But why not just - I don't know, cut off your finger, or something? I'm pretty sure that a lot of people who go to the Tower get to speak to Dean Potter. Or we could just talk to an auror and tell them what's up."

"Well, I suppose," said Lawrence. "But I think that they usually don't let you talk to him very much… and he must hear this kind of stuff all day. We need to stand out. And also… this might be a good opportunity for some payback on the Meroveni-Bowles. Opportunities like this, for a clever plot, don't come along every day."

"All right," Lawrence said. "So how are we going to sneak into the Tower, the most heavily-guarded place in Britain?" He took another bite out of his sandwich.

"I have an idea, I think," Annabeth said. "An idea for a plan." She picked up a piece of torn roll from her plate and rolled it into a ball between her fingers. "We want to solve a mystery and report a possible conspiracy, right? Recover a relic of the Founders of Hogwarts and return it to the rest of Hepzibah Smith's collection, and punish those responsible? And we also want to get Sammy and his siblings? And, of course, become famous and powerful?"

Lawrence nodded, chewing.

"Well, how can we do all of these things with one simple plan?" Annabeth squished the bread flat between two fingers. "Let me give you a hint: remember that big cabinet we saw in the Room of Requirement?"

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Note: How would you do it?

Chapter 26: Watchers

CARROW: Sir! Sir! What say you to the fact that our families are snapping in half, sir? I say to you what I have said a thousand times, and that is this: tradition is the glue which holds magical society together! When you burn away tradition, sweeping it off with Muggle machines and cold numbers, then you dissolve the ties which bind magical Britain! I myself have visited the Registrars of Marriages and Unions of Godric's Hollow and Diagon Alley, to name only two, and I am told that they have seen twice as many divorces this year as they saw in 1989! Twice as many! Homes are being broken, children are finding themselves Flooing back and forth on alternate weeks, and happy unions are being destroyed in the wake of all this haphazard and destructive change. So I ask you then, what say you to that?

[scattered applause]

POTTER: Thank you for that question. I do have a response. First, I believe that you show the same care for metaphor as you do for logic. Are we burning, sweeping, or dissolving? And if we're burning, how do we do that with cold numbers? Clear articulation is a sign of clear thought, and vice-versa.

[scattered applause]

CARROW: Mockery is no substitute for an answer! You-

HUGHES: Sir-

CARROW: You-

HUGHES: Sir, please let Mr. Potter finish speaking.

CARROW: You cannot-

HUGHES: Sir, please let-

CARROW: Yes, yes.

POTTER: I do have an answer. But before I give it, let me also point out that two points of data, two numbers, do not make a trend. There might have been unusually few divorces in 1989, for example. Or maybe the divorce rate was even higher in 1979. It's hard to compare anything unless you have more numbers. But that's not-

CARROW: The pleading of a child!

POTTER: But that's not the only flaw in your thinking, Mr. Carrow. There's a hoary old phrase to use at this point: correlation is-

CARROW: Yes, ply us with-

POTTER: Correlation-

CARROW: -your condescension, Mr. Potter.

HUGHES: Sir, I must ask you-

POTTER: Correlation-

HUGHES: Mr. Carrow-

POTTER: -is not causation. That means that there are many sorts of reasons why the divorce rate might have risen over a whole decade. Not every change in the world can be laid at my feet, and-

CARROW: All of this complicated jargon, but the words you need are so simple. Apologies have the virtue of brevity, as well.

HUGHES: Mr. Carrow, sir, I need to ask you to let Mr. Potter speak. Remember your name and the honour of your house, sir. We are here for a civil discussion.

CARROW: Yes.

DE KAMP: Mr.-

CARROW: My honour and that of my house is unbroken, Mr. Hughes.

HUGHES: Mr. Potter, please continue.

POTTER: Then let me just say this, then, Mr. Carrow: the largest flaw - no, the biggest mistake you're making is that you haven't even stopped to ask yourself whether or not this is a bad thing. If it is true, and if it is truly my fault, neither of which points I am willing to concede on the basis of two fiddly numbers out of context-

CARROW: You-

POTTER: -then it is almost certainly the result of money.

CARROW: Money?!

POTTER: Gringott's began issuing loans near the end of 1993, Mr. Carrow, and by 1995 the economy of magical Britain was twice as large.

CARROW: Money is only worth what it can be - and it cannot buy tradition, or happiness, or a family life. If we have made the trade you suggest, then I would say it is a bad bargain… and so much the worse for the shopkeep!

POTTER: You don't understand. The money has given people freedom. Even a small sum of money - the possibility of taking on the responsibility of debt - can be enough to allow someone to change their job or start a new business or even just change their situation. The freedom of money leads to a lot of other disruptive freedoms. Including the freedom to leave their spouse. People who might otherwise have felt trapped-

CARROW: You mudblood piece of-

HUGHES: Mr. Carrow! Mr. Carrow!

POTTER: Mr. Carrow, you seem-

HUGHES: Mr. Carrow, this is-

CARROW: She never-

HUGHES: Mr. Carrow!

CARROW: unintelligible

-Partial excerpt from the unedited transcript of the second of the Tower Debates on the Future of Magical Britain, as recorded by a certified-impartial Quotes Quill.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

"I know it's a bit unfair," Hermione Granger said, staring at the five Honourable, "but it certainly does seem that we tend to find you lot in skeevy little places, doing skeevy little things." She glanced pointedly down at the floor, where trickles of golden potion were slowly spreading around under the feet of Margaret Bulstrode, Edgar Erasmus, Geoffrey Gem, and his two assistants. She could smell the shrivelfig. Euphoria Elixir.

"Auror Kwannon?" Hermione called over her shoulder, past where Hyori was standing at the door. The Returned witch stepped aside to admit the auror, without ever taking her eyes or wand or glower off of the captured wizards and witches. Kwannon also had to edge past the gentleman she'd brought with her from the DMLE, Gerald. He was some sort of recorder, taking notes of raids like this one. An ineffectual attempt at holding aurors accountable, Hermione thought. Kwannon looked irritated at the whole production.

The aurors feel like they should be running the show, first through the door. But there's just no reason to let them take those kind of risks, not when I'm here, she thought. She glanced over at the auror again. Kwannon was relatively tall, considering her Chinese heritage, with a round face, a scattering of light freckles, and a flat nose. She was one of Alastor's, and was usually in the Tower. For the time being, though, she was here on Harry's behalf, along with four more aurors from the DMLE. Harry had needed someone here, after all - needed some eyes and ears on her Honourable hunt… what would he do with himself otherwise, locked up in that Tower and buried in healing and research, if he couldn't divert himself with some crude manipulations of everyone around him?

Not that manipulation, per se, was her complaint. It was just… Harry never learned. After their first year, including the trial and the troll and that terrible time at the end, he never really changed. He just became more… well, Harry-like. He hadn't learned the real lesson she thought he'd take away: if you try to use secret knowledge to manipulate complex situations about which you have incomplete information, then things will get very bad, very quickly. It was very hard for any person to be smart enough to manage that - and it was stupid to try when you had friends. It was "nihil supernum," after all, not "nihil par."

But the stubborn man hadn't learned then, and so Walpurgisnacht had happened, and he still hasn't learned, she thought, bitterly. Even after the price we paid. Hermione almost lifted her hand to touch her neck, but stopped as she realized what she was doing. No time for this sort of dithering.

She brought her thoughts back to the present situation. Time for me to butt out a bit. I'll make myself her asset, rather than her superior. She's probably better at this than I, anyway.

"Auror Kwannon, this isn't really my sort of thing," she said, turning and smiling at the auror, slightly lifting her shoulders to indicate her ignorance about the next proper thing to do. "You were kind enough to let me pop through here quickly, to keep the miscreants here… maybe you could take the lead from here?"

"Yes, well…" said the auror, looking around the room before focusing back in on the five Honourable. "This is some trouble, here."

Gem noticeably shrank back into himself, seeming almost to fold his thin body over. The witch and wizard that were his assistants took things a little bit more in stride - as though stunned and out of place, with confused expressions. Hermione was fairly sure they were still riding down a dose of Euphoria.

Erasmus, on the other hand, puffed up his chest. He was red in the face, and with the colouring of his hair, he looked humorously similar to a large carrot. "There's no crime in printing and distributing a newsletter, or in conducting private researches, I think. Even in today's Britain!"

Kwannon turned her sharp attention to the researcher. "Mr. Erasmus, you are correct. However, it is illegal to operate a private Floo network, it is illegal to conduct dangerous research within one hundred meters of a residence, and it is extremely illegal to sell Euphoric Elixir without a license."

"All unjust prohibitions!" said Erasmus. He had brilliant blue eyes that were narrowed in indignation. To emphasize his point, he thumped his fist down on the stack of boxes he'd been carrying when Hermione had torn up the entrance hatch and knocked down their door. "Who is the Government to say what I do with a Floo, where I can do my research, or what potions I brew, eh? My research is my research!"

"I recall your research, sir," said Kwannon, her mouth tight.

The former Tower researcher had been studying the construction of magical machines, Hermione recalled, before he had been fired, his research confiscated, and key memories Obliviated. Erasmus had ignored safety concerns entirely, and had insisted on just bullying through and continuing to build his wind-machines. They used fluid dynamics: tight swirls of air spinning as gears, fed by small warming columns of heat from below; flywheels of pressurized zones to store and transfer energy; and shifts between small turbulent flows and laminar flows as switches.

The machines had been brilliant - Erasmus was brilliant - but they had also been maddeningly dangerous. One Ventus could power them for days, and the very first thing they were designed to do was consume waste matter of any type and incinerate it for more power. If Erasmus had moved his investigations of Muggle science out of engineering and aerodynamics, and into something like computer programming… the danger had been unbelievable, even by magical standards. He was almost a cartoonish figure: the mad scientist with no concern for consequences. Harry had not only been apoplectic, he'd been outright offended.

Hermione supposed that the setbacks they'd given Erasmus, including the changes to his memory, were probably enough to ensure everyone's safety. But to see him right back at it, only now without any supervision… they'd need to do something, somehow. It needed thought. For now, at least, it looked like Erasmus wouldn't be a danger for a while.

"In the States, anyone can set up a Floo. It's not right that there's only one Floo Network in Britain," offered Margaret Bulstrode. She was a beautiful young woman, but clearly quite out of her depth. Hermione knew Margaret, slightly - she'd been several years ahead at Hogwarts, and the aurors in charge of investigating the Diagon bombing had brought her before the Wizengamot for examination on the basis of an informant's accusations. Nothing had come of it.

"I wouldn't know about that, I'm afraid," said Kwannon, her voice hard. "But I do know it's illegal here, just like Faux Floo is illegal. Is that the genuine two-Sickles-a-scoop on your mantel?"

"Yes," said Erasmus, puffing out his cheeks.

"Mm," said Kwannon, noncommittally. She walked around the room, looking sharply into corners and at everything around. "What else you have here, eh? Come on, Gerald." She headed through the other door, into a hallway or another room. Gerald followed her with his floating parchment and Quotes Quill, looking nervous.

"This is a private facility," called out the weasely Gem, hugging himself. He'd put down the crate he'd been holding. "You have no call to go snooping…" He trailed off, uneasily. His fear of the Goddess and Hermione's supernatural air of innocence were probably confusing him. That sometimes happened.

"She's an auror," said Hermione. "The Tower and I have proper search warrants and habeas corpus and seizure rules planned out, but we haven't gotten there yet. For now, you're stuck with the traditional system, as we found it. Seems to mostly date back to the eighteenth century, with some modern bits like Hit Wizards stuck on. But tradition is best, after all… isn't that right?"

Need to taunt as a distraction… best not take it too far, though. Susie seemed to think it was funny, though, smirking as she walked to the crates of copies of Unbreakable Honour and sat on one. " 'Good for thee, but not for me,' as the saying goes, love." said the Returned.

Erasmus huffed again. "Under any system of justice, Muggle or magical, this is out of order."

Hermione approached him. "How so? I'd be interested to hear you defend this, Edgar." She gestured at the crate of broken potion, and clasped her hands in front of herself. "Did your research ever lead you to encounter the notion of 'wireheading,' I wonder?"

"You were famous for fighting bullies, back when you were at Hogwarts," said Margaret, suddenly and loudly. "S.P.H.E.W and all that. But now you are a bully."

Ah, that'll do nicely. Hermione smiled again, and turned to face Bulstrode. She approached very close, and stared at the woman. She was a little taller than Margaret, and she knew she was quite intimidating. She let the smile fade from her face, and lifted a finger. She poked it into Margaret's chest, and said - coldly, now - "Don't hide behind loose categorizations. Say what you mean. You're being persecuted, are you?" She plucked at Margaret's robe at the shoulder, and then again at one of the pockets, contemptuously and dismissively… as though the woman were a bit of lint. "You and all of Draco's loathsome death-worshippers, piling all your prejudices and ignorance up into a single lot." She walked around Margaret as she spoke, and took the opportunity to surreptitiously drop a button - one she'd removed from Margaret's pocket, and palmed - into her own robes.

"I'll say what I mean, all right," replied Margaret. Her voice barely shook. "You lot have taken over. And you've done a lot of good things. But there's a natural order to the world, and you've broken it. You've… you've done some of the darkest of rituals. It's the only way things even make sense. And you're eating up all the rest of the world, state by state. If you keep going, the world won't even be recognizable… no traditions left, no people thinking their own thoughts in their own ways… you want everyone to be the same, like the porcelain dolls that come out of the Tower. 'Rejuvenation'... it's just control and replacement!"

"Draco has always had a silver tongue," said Hermione, scornfully. She's just parroting back what she hears. This was the danger of letting things go this way, Harry… they're cementing in these ideas. It's hard enough to get people on our side, but to win over those who actually hate us this much?

You knew I'd never agree with this plan. That I'd point out it was extravagant and risky and impractical. The slow victory is better than the fast loss, Harry.

But Harry wasn't here, and there was no point venting now. Bend before the storm, and surprise her.

"You might be right in some ways, Ms. Bulstrode," she said, walking away. She saw Hyori raise an eyebrow from her position by the entrance, and flashed a quick smile at the Returned. Hermione turned back around to face the Honourable. "It's dangerous to discard a lot of traditions. Many of them survive from century to century because they serve an important purpose. Memetic survival: mutation, variation, and evolution. 'Unconscious memes have ensured their own survival by virtue of the same qualities of ruthlessness that successful genes display,' " she quoted. (The Selfish Gene by Richard Dawkins, page 198, her brain automatically supplied). "It's something we should be more careful about, and we want to avoid when we can. Was there any specific tradition that you are unhappy about losing?"

Margaret was silent for a long moment. Hermione folded her arms, and waited patiently. It wasn't even an act: she was honestly interested to hear the answer.

"How about Quidditch?" said Margaret, after a while. "The Tower wants to get rid of that."

"Well, he did want to change it, yes," Hermione said. "Not get rid of it. Harry isn't much for sports in general, I'm afraid, and I don't think he ever quite understood it - especially the snitch. Muggles have a similar sort of thing called test cricket, but I doubt Harry has ever played or even watched it."

"They sacked all the Quidditch regulators!" said Margaret in reply, strength coming into her voice. "Closed down the whole games section of the Ministry!"

"That wasn't the Tower, that was a decision by Minister Fudge," said Hermione. But when Margaret and Erasmus gave her a look, she smiled slightly. "But yes, he supported it. As I recall, though, Quidditch is doing just fine… better than ever, in fact, now that it's being run privately. Most of the same people working for it, I think."

Kwannon returned at that moment, Gerald in tow, shaking her head. "Fairly plain about the research being done here, and the Euphoria being brewed. We'll get some people in here to collect all this, but I think you should all try to think of a good solicitor, if you know one." She headed up to the entrance, and waved in the aurors who were standing idle in the corridor. "Come on through. Back rooms there… bag up the lot. Leave the experiments inside the circles until we can have someone bring them out with precautions."

"I imagine they know some people who can help," said Susie.

"Malfoy," said Hyori from behind Hermione, scornfully.

"Be careful with my research," said Erasmus, urgently. He was turning red again with anxiety. "I'm within a hair of a working Zimara machine!"

Perpetual motion? Maybe I can stay and take a look, thought Hermione.

"Any way we can help, Hedley?" she asked, hopefully. "We can stick around if you would like some assistance?"

"Thank you, but I think we have it in hand," said Kwannon. Hermione probably should have let her go first; there would have been relatively little danger. Lesson learned.

"Then I suppose we do have things we can get up to. Thank you," said Hermione. She nodded at her Returned, and they all headed for the exit.

It was true, after all. They had some parchments to read. As they made their way out, Hermione reached into her robe and picked up the Everlasting Eye. When she'd seen Bulstrode out on the streets of Knockturn Alley, it had been easy enough to step aside, slip on the Cloak of Invisibility, and sprint on around ahead of her. She'd dropped the listening device into Margaret's pocket after tripping her with an invisible foot.

"Let's find out who escaped our raid, shall we?" she asked the two Returned witches. Susie smiled.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

We are faced, right from the beginning, with a difficult task. It is a task so immense that most wizards never even notice it, any more than they notice their eyelids. Indeed, when I began this chapter, I sought out dozens of the most learned wizards in Britain, only to discover that no more than one or two had ever given any thought to the problem. Madame Hopkirk of the Department of Mysteries herself was able only to point me to three or four dusty volumes of consideration - none of which I could read (the obstacle was the same one previously encountered, dear reader, when I attempted to research the history of Hogwarts: no consideration is given to those for whom the Interdict is a forever-insuperable obstacle).

Subsequent conversations will allow us to piece together some basic ideas, if they must be rudimentary of necessity. So then: what is magic? The physical realization of an inner spirit? The action of a daemon working on one's behalf? A demand made on some hidden set of rules to the universe? We set our education and wits to the task of explaining many things we might see in magic:

A large proportion of magical effects conform, depend, or otherwise interact with the emotions, expectations, wishes, or willpower of the caster.

Magic seems to operate almost entirely on a human scale, even including wholly subjective aspects of modern life.

The linguistic components of spells are all well-suited to the human tongue, and most even seem to derive from Latin or Greek roots. The history of magic begins in Greece, as Madame Bagshot has instructed us, but was that necessity or coincidence?

Magically-created matter is mundane matter in most respects.

Magic interferes with Muggle machines in some unknown way, yet to be discovered or classified, and thus seems inherently inimical to machinery in a spiritual sense.

The ability of humans to do magic varies, with most people unable to do any magic at all, others having only the very tiny magic of a Squib, and some having enough magic to cast spells. Many plants and animals also possess magic where others do not.

Magic is hereditary, and so must be a trait like hair color or height that is passed from parent to child.

It is widely known that magic has been decreasing over time, which means that it must be going somewhere.

When these phenomena are fully internalized and realized, we may thus see that the daemon theory of which we spoke earlier must be the correct one. It explains all of the above conditions, as the daemons consume magic to live, make war on rival machines, live within the body to touch upon the mind, and are passed from parent to child like a Sallowfax infection.

- excerpted from Chapter Three of A Squib's-Eye View, by A. F. Leiding

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

It is abundantly clear that Mr. Leiding is not only a Squib, but also a fool. We may pity him for his limitations in magic, but we should pity him even more for his limitations in reasoning.

It is impossible to understand the true nature of magic. Atlantis' fall put the source of that knowledge out of time and out of our reach. This may be the ultimate tragedy of this book: left with no purpose, what else is Mr. Leiding to do, but construct fantasies and try to know the unknowable?

-excerpted from American Mage's review of A Squib's-Eye View